<?xml version="1.0"?>
<simplesect>
<para>
    Auto-shoot mode enables automatic photo capture at specified intervals, making
    it ideal for time-lapse photography, surveillance applications, or any scenario
    where continuous photo capture is needed without manual intervention.
</para>

<refsect1>
    <title>Enabling Auto-Shoot</title>
    <para>
      To enable auto-shoot mode, use the <option>--auto</option> or
      <option>-a</option> command-line option:
    </para>
    <screen>
cheese --auto
    </screen>
    <para>
      By default, photos are captured every 1000 milliseconds (1 second) and saved
      to the default photo directory. You can customize both the interval and the
      save location.
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Configuring Shoot Interval</title>
    <para>
      Use the <option>--shoot-interval</option> or <option>-i</option> option to
      specify the interval between photos in milliseconds:
    </para>
    <screen>
cheese --auto --shoot-interval 5000
    </screen>
    <para>
      This example captures a photo every 5 seconds. The interval can be set to
      any positive value, allowing for very rapid capture (e.g., 100ms for 10
      photos per second) or slow time-lapse (e.g., 60000ms for 1 photo per minute).
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Specifying Save Directory</title>
    <para>
      Use the <option>--save-dir</option> or <option>-o</option> option to specify
      a custom directory for saving captured photos:
    </para>
    <screen>
cheese --auto --save-dir /path/to/photos
    </screen>
    <para>
      If the specified directory does not exist, Cheese will automatically create
      it along with any necessary parent directories. If directory creation fails,
      an error will be displayed and auto-shoot will not start.
    </para>
    <para>
      Example: Capture photos every 2 seconds and save them to a custom directory:
    </para>
    <screen>
cheese --auto --shoot-interval 2000 --save-dir ~/timelapse/2025-04
    </screen>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Flash and Sound Settings</title>
    <para>
      Auto-shoot mode respects your current Cheese settings for flash and sound:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If flash is enabled in preferences, it will fire for each captured photo
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          If shutter sound is enabled, it will play for each captured photo
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      These settings can be configured through Cheese's preferences dialog before
      starting auto-shoot mode.
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>File Naming</title>
    <para>
      Photos captured in auto-shoot mode follow the same naming convention as
      manually captured photos. Each photo is given a unique filename based on
      the current date and time, ensuring no files are overwritten.
    </para>
    <para>
      The filename format typically includes:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Date and time stamp</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Sequential number for photos taken in the same second</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Appropriate file extension (e.g., .jpg, .png)</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Stopping Auto-Shoot</title>
    <para>
      To stop auto-shoot mode, simply close the Cheese window or quit the
      application. There is no separate command to stop auto-shoot while keeping
      Cheese running.
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Use Cases</title>
    <para>
      Auto-shoot mode is useful for various scenarios:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <emphasis>Time-lapse photography</emphasis>: Capture photos at regular
          intervals to create time-lapse videos
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <emphasis>Security monitoring</emphasis>: Continuous photo capture for
          surveillance purposes
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <emphasis>Documentation</emphasis>: Automatic capture of periodic events
          or processes
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <emphasis>Scientific recording</emphasis>: Automated data collection at
          regular intervals
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Combining with Other Features</title>
    <para>
      Auto-shoot mode can be combined with other Cheese features for enhanced
      functionality:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <option>--borderless</option>: Run in minimal borderless window while
          capturing photos
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <option>--topmost</option>: Keep window on top to monitor capture status
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <option>--noactionbar</option>: Minimize UI for long-running captures
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      Example: Run auto-shoot in a minimal borderless window, capturing every 3
      seconds:
    </para>
    <screen>
cheese --auto --shoot-interval 3000 --save-dir ~/captures --borderless --noactionbar
      </screen>
</refsect1>
</simplesect>
