<?xml version="1.0"?>
<simplesect>
<para>
    Borderless mode allows Cheese to run without window decorations, creating a
    minimal UI perfect for always-visible webcam monitoring or integration into
    custom workflows. In borderless mode, the window can be resized very small
    (down to 64x36 pixels) and positioned anywhere on the screen.
</para>

<refsect1>
    <title>Starting in Borderless Mode</title>
    <para>
      To start Cheese in borderless mode, use the <option>--borderless</option>
      or <option>-b</option> command-line option:
    </para>
    <screen>
cheese --borderless
    </screen>
    <para>
      You can also toggle borderless mode at runtime using the <keycap>F4</keycap>
      keyboard shortcut.
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Window Controls</title>
    <para>
      In borderless mode, the window can be controlled using the mouse:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <emphasis>Left mouse button</emphasis>: Click and drag to move the window
          around the screen.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <emphasis>Right mouse button</emphasis>: Click and drag from any corner
          to resize the window. The window will automatically maintain the camera's
          aspect ratio to ensure the preview fills the available space without gaps.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      The window is divided into four quadrants for corner detection:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Top-left quadrant: Resize from top-left corner</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Top-right quadrant: Resize from top-right corner</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Bottom-left quadrant: Resize from bottom-left corner</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Bottom-right quadrant: Resize from bottom-right corner</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</refsect1>

<refsect1>
    <title>Aspect Ratio Preservation</title>
    <para>
      When resizing in borderless mode, Cheese automatically adjusts the window
      size to maintain the camera's aspect ratio. This ensures that:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The video preview fills the available viewport space without gaps
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The window size accounts for UI elements (header bar, action bar,
          thumbnails) to provide accurate sizing
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          The window is automatically patched on startup to remove any initial gaps
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      The aspect ratio is calculated from the camera's current video format, ensuring
      the preview always displays correctly regardless of the camera resolution.
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Minimum Window Size</title>
    <para>
      The window has a minimum size of 64x36 pixels to ensure basic functionality
      and visibility. Attempts to resize below this minimum will be automatically
      constrained.
    </para>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Combining with Other Features</title>
    <para>
      Borderless mode works well when combined with other mini-UI features:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <option>--noactionbar</option>: Hide the action bar for an even more
          minimal interface
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <option>--nothumbnails</option>: Hide thumbnails to maximize preview space
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <option>--follow</option>: Make the window follow the cursor, perfect
          for small overlay windows
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <option>--topmost</option>: Keep the window always on top for monitoring
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <para>
      Example: Start Cheese in a minimal borderless window that follows the cursor:
    </para>
    <screen>
cheese --borderless --noactionbar --nothumbnails --follow --topmost
    </screen>
  </refsect1>

  <refsect1>
    <title>Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
    <para>
      The following keyboard shortcuts are available in borderless mode:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <keycap>F4</keycap>: Toggle borderless mode on/off
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <keycap>F5</keycap>: Toggle action bar visibility
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <keycap>F6</keycap>: Toggle thumbnails visibility
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <keycap>h</keycap>: Select Flip effect
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <keycap>v</keycap>: Select Flip-Vertical effect
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
</refsect1>
</simplesect>
